<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>echo &#34;Rafael Moreira&#34;</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on echo &#34;Rafael Moreira&#34;</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Rafael Moreira</copyright><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Who am I? I am an young DevOps Engineer eager to learn new tecnhologies and patterns in this big world of Cloud Computing and constant technological advancements.
I am from Portugal and I have a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Informatics Engineering from ISEP. I have a background (high-school) in Sciences and Technologies.
I am currently taking a Master&amp;rsquo;s Degree in Software Engineering, also at ISEP.
What do I do? I work with multiple technology stacks to deliver development changes to multiple environments (CI/CD), as smooth as changes can be.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-am-i&#34;&gt;Who am I?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am an young DevOps Engineer eager to learn new tecnhologies and patterns in this big world of Cloud Computing and constant technological advancements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am from Portugal and I have a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Informatics Engineering from ISEP. I have a background (high-school) in Sciences and Technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently taking a Master&amp;rsquo;s Degree in Software Engineering, also at ISEP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-do-i-do&#34;&gt;What do I do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work with multiple technology stacks to deliver development changes to multiple environments (CI/CD), as smooth as changes can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also design and maintain infrastructure in cloud vendors such as AWS and Azure. I have built custom infrastructures, using services such as EC2, ElasticLoadBalancers, RDS, and I have build Kubernetes infrastructures, with self-managed FOSS technologies and AWS Managed services (EKS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work on tools to ease developer&amp;rsquo;s problems during their work, to prevent catastrophes and minimize the impact of threats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-technologies-do-i-work-with&#34;&gt;What technologies do I work with?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work with Kubernetes (K8s), Docker and other containerization technologies (Podman, Containerd).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am proficient in BASH, Typescript (mainly used in Infrastructure as Code or &lt;em&gt;Kubernetes as Code&lt;/em&gt; projects) and I can manage Linux-based systems (Ubuntu, Alma Linux, CentOS, Amazon Linux, amongst others).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-am-i-currently-learning&#34;&gt;What am I currently learning?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently improving my Python skills, to begin replacing some of my BASH scripts with Python (this topic deserves a post itself) and I am also learning Go, due to the fact that during my experiments with K8s I have had the need to develop custom tools, such as controllers, and Go feels like the &lt;em&gt;go-to&lt;/em&gt; language to use for this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan on learning Terraform and improve my Ansible skills later, to go full cloud-agnostic (in conjunction with K8s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-do-i-store-my-code&#34;&gt;Where do I store my code?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/rafaelmoreira1180778&#34;&gt;GitLab&lt;/a&gt; to host my code for all my projects, alongside multiple thoughts and small scripts that I develop daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/RafaelMoreira1180778&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; but I don&amp;rsquo;t host any code there. Coming from a daily user of GitLab, I prefer the CI/CD mechanisms of it compared to GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-may-i-contact-you&#34;&gt;How may I contact you?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;../contact/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Contact Me&amp;rdquo; webpage&lt;/a&gt; of my blog for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Me</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>LinkedIn I am available at LinkedIn, where I share my accomplishments and other relevant information for my work history and academic record.
Email You can email me at rafael@homelabrafael.com.
Resume Here is my more detailed resume, with more information about my work history and academic history, alongside a very small exposure of the technologies I am proficient at.</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;linkedin&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/paulorafaelmoreira/&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, where I share my accomplishments and other relevant information for my work history and academic record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;email&#34;&gt;Email&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can email me at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:rafael@homelabrafael.com&#34;&gt;rafael@homelabrafael.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resume&#34;&gt;Resume&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is my &lt;em&gt;more detailed&lt;/em&gt; resume, with more information about my work history and academic history, alongside a very small exposure of the technologies I am proficient at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./resume.svg&#34; alt=&#34;Resume&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
